## Mohammed Maviya Ansari

Location: Mumbai E-mail: ansarimaviya@gmail.com

Website: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/ansari-maviya-38645276/">https://www.linkedin.com/in/ansari-maviya-38645276/</a>

#### **SUMMARY**

Solution-driven professional more than 3.5 years in highly collaborative work environment, finding solutions to challenges and focused on customer satisfaction. Proven experience developing consumer-focused web sites using Angular 8, React JS, CodeIgniter 4, Laravel 8, HTML5, CSS3, JQuery, PHP and JavaScript. Great Experience in building products for Desktop and Mobile users, meeting highest standards for web design, user experience, best practices, usability and speed. Responding to challenges by designing and developing solutions and building web applications aligned to customer's services. Translating solutions into code and working across many different APIs, third- party integrations and databases.

## WORK EXPERIENCE

## ➤ Kshan Tech Soft Pvt Ltd – (Career Now Brands)

Apr 2021 —Present

Mobile: +91 8898266547

PHP Laravel Developer/Software Engineer

- Working with US based client CNB (Career Now Brands) on their projects.
- Worked as a team to develop and maintain a highly sophisticated multi-state foreclosure processing application
- Supported technical team members in designing and development of interactive web features.
- Assisted in implementation of new features and modifications to existing features.
- Participated in all phases of project development lifecycle to produce working designs.
- Provided technical assistance for development of legacy websites and sites on new framework.
- Hands on working experience on Laravel 8, PHP, Fuel PHP, VUE JS, Laravel NOVA admin 3, etc.

### > Roster Buster RB Group

Jan 2021 — Apr 2021

Software Engineer

- Gained working experience in Laravel Airline based domain project
- Gained working knowledge of JIRA, Confluence, etc.
- Gained Expertise in programming capabilities including Laravel 8, Rest API Development, AWS server, MySQL, Unit Test and JavaScript and other libraries as needed

## > TTH Consulting Services

Nov 2019 — Dec 2020

Jr PHP Web and Software Developer

- Experience in building REST APIs
- Expertise working with data structures and algorithms
- Analyzed requirements and designed, developed and implemented software applications for multiple websites
- Tested websites and performed troubleshooting prior to deployment. Designed, implemented and monitored web pages and sites for continuous improvement
- Successfully Designed and executed security measures such as encryption.
- Created powerful Content Management Systems to serve as interface for client. Planned and engineered RESTful web services to manipulate dynamic datasets. Streamlined deployment process by developing continuous integration tools
- Gained Expertise in programming capabilities including PHP, Laravel and CodeIgniter, Rest API Development, AZURE server, SQL and JavaScript and other libraries as needed

#### > JTech Ventures

Jul 2018 — Oct 2019

Full Stack Developer

Mohammed Maviya Ansari 1

- Attained Knowledge in Building, testing and deploying scalable, highly available and modular software products. Tested websites and performed troubleshooting prior to deployment
- Administered, supported and monitored databases by proactively resolving database issues and maintaining servers
- Received confidence in performing troubleshooting of technical issues within production environment. Regularly updated my knowledge of latest industry trends in web development and related technologies
- Improved proficiency in programming capabilities including PHP, Laravel, CodeIgniter, SQL and JavaScript and other libraries as needed

#### **EDUCATION**

## **Bachelor of Information Technology**

Jul 2015 — Jun 2018

K.C. College Of Engineering & MSRC

7.30 CGPA

**Diploma in Information Technology** 

Jul 2011 — Jan 2015

M.H. Saboo Siddik Polytechnic

63.06%

SSC

Jan 2010 — Jun 2011

Anjumna-I-Islam Kurla Boys High School

87.45%

#### **SKILLS**

- PHP
- Web Development
- API Development
- Codeigniter 3/4
- Laravel 8
- Ajax and JSON
- HTML5 & CSS3
- JavaScript
- Jquery
- Angular 8
- Software Development
- React JS
- Python
- Android
- IONIC

# ACCOMPLISHMENT / PROJECTS

- coroebus.in/b2b: This is gamification platform Client Web Panel based on kpi and it is developed in codeignitor, php, angular 8, ionic 4, api, jquery, MySQL, AWS, JSON
- coroebus.in/b2b-tgc: This is gamification platform Admin and Master Web Panel and it is developed in codeignitor, php, bootstrap 4, api, jquery, MySQL, AWS, JSON
- <u>www.startupfraternity.in</u> in PHP, Laravel, jQuery, CSS, HTML, MYSQL, JSON, AJAX, JavaScript
- <u>www.jtechventures.in</u>
- www.laxmibeautystores.com
- JNRoadLines in PHP, Laravel, jQuery, CSS, HTML, MYSQL, JSON, AJAX
- <u>SindhiWeds</u> Matrimonial Website in ReactJS, NodeJS, MongoDB.
- <u>egomedia.in</u> in PHP, jQuery, Ajax, JSON, MYSQL, etc with client and employee panel. For maintaining and managing the hoardings
- www.skns.in
- Final year project in Engineering on "Automated Library System using Data Mining with Client Server Architecture" in PHP, HTML, CSS, JQuery, SQL, JavaScript, JSON

Mohammed Maviya Ansari 2

- Final year project in Diploma on "Educational Based Social Networking Website" in ASP.NET, C# & SQL Server Database
- Other Projects:
  - o ExamCell in PHP, Laravel, jQuery, CSS, HTML, MySQL, Javascript
  - o Ecommerce in PHP, jQuery, CSS, HTML, SQL

Mohammed Maviya Ansari